# Jeet Patel

(628) 777-8142 ♦ jshpatel@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ <u>linkedin.com/in/jshpatel</u> ♦ <u>jeetp465.github.io</u>

### PROFILE

A data-driven individual with 4 years of analytics experience working for one of the oldest retail chains

Specialties: Statistical Exploration, Machine Learning, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing, Data Visualization

Technologies: Python, SQL, R, PySpark, PyTorch, TensorFlow, BigQuery, Teradata, Tableau, Adobe Analytics

### **EDUCATION**

University of California, DavisSan Francisco, CAMaster of Science, Business AnalyticsExpected Jun 2022Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), KanpurKanpur, INDBachelor of Technology, Computer Science and EngineeringJun 2013 – Jul 2017

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **American Eagle Outfitters**

San Francisco, CA

Data Scientist, Practicum Project

Sept 2021 – present

Partnered with multi-billion dollar fashion retailer to optimize store-to-store inventory transfer strategy

- Conducted EDA on 522K products identifying potential incremental revenue opportunities worth 83M
- Forecasted product-level demand at all stores, improving AEO's forecasting processes by 12%
- Achieved a 32x reduction in experimentation time of deep learning models using parallel processing
- Built data processing pipelines for pre-processing 270 GB+ data using Google BigQuery

Sears Holdings India Pune, IND

Senior Business Analyst

Aug 2017 – Jul 2021

- Designed an MLP-LSTM based neural network followed by a Mixture Density Network to forecast demand at a product level, gaining a relative improvement of 43.6%
- Implemented Autoencoder for anomaly detection, achieving an overlap of 58% with rule-based model
- Scaled a rule-based anomaly detection model from Python to Google BigQuery, reducing the runtime by
   64x, and integrated it into a Tableau dashboard to be used by business stakeholders
- Developed a Question Answering model using Transformer architectures like Bert and Longformer for assisting users on querying terms and conditions of Sears Home Services manual
- Deduplicated & clustered ~100M Sears members into households for targeted marketing
- Developed scripts to migrate project from Teradata to BigQuery, reducing the processing time by ~50%
- Gathered requirements and created ETL pipelines & MicroStrategy dashboards to track business KPIs

# ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

# **Projects:**

<u>FIFA Position Prediction</u> - Predicted the position of soccer players using Random Forest with a **68%** F-1 score <u>Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis</u> - Predicted polarity of aspect terms in reviews using LSTM with a **55%** F-1 score <u>Neural Diary</u> - Condensed long videos into salient frames and generated corresponding text descriptions <u>Real-Time Vehicle Recognition</u> - Segmented and classified vehicles from live video stream with a mean **73%** IOU

#### Leadership:

- Led the curriculum committee of the Director's Student Advisory Committee (DSAC)
- Served as the coordinator of Dance Club, handling a budget of INR 100K to conduct workshops & events

## **Activities:**

- Beta Gamma Sigma, International Honor Society for **Top 20%** students in AASCB accredited B-Schools
- Top 10 UC Davis teams at Adobe Analytics Challenge'21 in partnership with The Walt Disney Company
- Won 1st prize in Sears Hackathon, implementing a supply chain framework on permissioned Block-Chain
- Won 1st prize in Decrypt'17, a case study competition, out of 300+ pan-India entries